[Music]
it is summertime and that means that the
wildflowers will soon be gone
[Music]
during this time i usually harvest what
last little bits of flowers i find
and also start to focus on my own garden
[Music]
yesterday i made the happy discovery of
wild chamomile growing among my
marigolds
[Music]
it is also known as pineapple weed and
like dandelions it's not necessarily
considered a gardener's friend
however many of these weeds are actually
quite useful and at times beneficial
it simply takes some knowledge of how to
forage and use them
for example dandelion petals are
actually rather sweet and tasty
and pineapple weed smells like a more
citrusy version of chamomile
plus it tastes
[Music]
amazing of course one of my favorite
plants for tea making is lavender
and i like to harvest and dry it
and keep it for the winter months when i
am missing spring
some lavender keeps its scent longer
than others
english lavender for example
doesn't always smell very strongly
however
i find it to be the best for tea making
[Music]
still i like to make a little bundle for
drying
all i find you have to do is pinch the
flowers between your fingers a little
bit
to release the scent or if i'm gonna
make tea i use a mortar
lavender tea is one of my absolute
favorites
i never get tired of it
even the busiest days require slow
moments
[Music]
though it's only the start of the summer
my herb garden is doing quite well it is
very abundant and i am excited to have
multiple harvests this year
[Music]
i love the process of tea making it is
so calming
and meditative
it is definitely a labor of love as you
have to harvest quite a lot of leaves to
make even one small jar of tea
but
in my mind it's definitely worth it
there are many ways to dry your tea
leaves
over here it's not very humid so i can
dry them out in the sun
within a day
however you can also use a dehydrator
which is quite useful for large batches
[Music]
if you are seeking to learn more about
tea making i highly recommend this book
i'll leave the link down below it was my
first introduction to understanding how
to grow and take care of tea plants
and it was very inspiring to me
here are some of my favorite
combinations of tea
[Music]
if you are not already a tea maker
i highly recommend experimenting with
some simple herbs that are easy to grow
like mint
it is so wonderful to experience growing
a plant and harvesting and consuming it
it really
keeps you connected to the natural cycle
[Music]
while i embrace and accept the
importance of every season
summer
is complicated for me
[Music]
while i spend most of it by the lake and
love the feeling of the sun tickling my
neck
i'm always aware of the possibility of
wildfires
there's evidence of them all over the
county
and
so many trees have been lost
wildfires can occur naturally but
many of them are started by accidents or
by carelessness
my greatest fear is fire
since i have some memories associated
with it that were highly traumatic
but if i ever find myself worrying too
much about the unknown i try to stop and
remember the spring
nature doesn't stop growing just because
of the fear of a future that may or may
not happen
it blooms
and thrives and does what it can with
the time that it has
this is something that
i
need to remember
[Music]
you